Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
在上一集里
Few things of value come without a price.
天下没有白吃的午餐
What is it that you wish in return?
你想要什么回报？
Only to be a Decepticon once again.
小人只愿重回霸天虎之列
Now, what will we be fishing for today, my liege?
这次您想知道什么呢 我的君王？
Starscream's true motives.
红蜘蛛的真实意图！
Ah, the high-and-mighty Skyquake.
啊 高贵强大的天震
You shall bow to my command.
你应该听我号令！
Symbiosis. Hahaha... I can feel it!
融为一体 哈哈哈…我感觉到了！
Awkward.
完了…
I will allow you to return to our ranks.
我允许你重回我们的队伍
Oh! Thank the Allspark!
我的个娘啊…感谢火种源！
You know, I might not be the first human on Cybertron,
嘿 别看我没能当成首个踏上塞博特恩的人类
but I can still be the first human exchange student.
可我还是能成为历史上第一个人类交换生！
Why didn't you tell us about the Omega keys before?
干嘛不早点告诉我们“终极之钥”的事？
You probably didn't notice,
或许你没注意到
but things have been kind of intense around here lately.
最近情势有些紧张
So, you guys could really be going home soon, huh?
这么说…你们真的能在短期内回家了？
Don't worry, Raf.
别担心 拉夫
You'll come visit!
你随时能来看我们
Once we get our place set up, he can bunk with us.
等咱们安顿好住处之后 他也可以随时来访
Right, Bulk?
对吧 小隔？
Uh, Miko?
呃…神子
You are taking me with you, right?
你会带我去的 对吧？
Aren't we getting ahead of ourselves here?
咱们是不是高兴得早了点儿？
Not only do we lack any actual method of reaching Cybertron,
别说咱们现在无法到达塞博特恩
but Starscream now controls the sole means of our planet's restoration.
就连唯一能复兴星球的工具都在红蜘蛛的手里
As far as we know.
那是我们仅有的情报…
You think Starscream's rejoined the Cons?
您的意思是红蜘蛛可能又回虎窝了？
He might've used the Omega keys to buy back Megatron's favor.
他可能会用“终极之钥”去讨威震天的欢心
Hmph. Without first trying to sell them to the highest bidder?
哼…他就是个奸商 想看谁出价更高
It wouldn't surprise me if he had the nerve to contact us and...
我敢说他不久就会联系我们 并且…
Okay, that's weird.
好吧 救大半仙！
Is it Starscream?
真是红蜘蛛啊？
No. It is Dreadwing.
不 是骇翼
And he wants to meet.
他想和我们见一面
Drop your weapons!
放下武器！
Hands where we can see them!
举起手来！
I am not here to fight,
我不是来战斗的
but to give you this.
而是来给你们送这个
The Forge of Solus Prime.
卓天越之锤？
Could be rigged to blow.
可能装着炸弹
Dreadwing,
骇翼
what do you ask in return?
你想要什么回报？
Only that you use it wisely.
你能善加使用就是最好的报答
And? The Omega keys?
那么“终极之钥”呢？
In Megatron's possession,
在威震天手里
under heaviest guard.
守卫森严
Scream did make a deal with the Cons.
小红真的和霸天虎勾结了！
Why?
你用意何在？
A shadow of disgrace has been cast upon the Decepticons.
霸天虎之名已被他们玷污了
It is a cause I no longer wish to be part of.
我不愿再与之为伍
Then I appeal to you again.
那么 我再次请求你
Join us and help end this conflict once and for all.
加入我们 同心协力 让这场战争彻底终结！
Betraying my kind
背叛我的族群…
is not the same as accepting yours.
不代表就要加入你的队伍
It's no Star Saber,
这虽然不是星辰剑
but I bet it can shatter Megatron's blade
但我敢说它肯定能砸碎威震天的剑
and put some dents into that ugly mug of his.
顺便砸扁他那张丑脸！
It's not that kind of hammer.
这锤子不是那么用的
With the Decepticons in possession of all four Omega keys,
既然四块“终极之钥”都在霸天虎手里
a more appropriate use of the Forge would be to use it to replicate our own.
那我们不妨用这锤子复制出新的！
Even with such power,
即便锤子有这种力量
their reconstruction would require a level of expertise I do not possess.
我也没有足够的专业知识来进行这种高级复制
I guess we better hope Megatron doesn't destroy the keys
那我们只能祈祷威震天不会毁掉所有钥匙
to prevent anyone from ever going home.
以防其他人可以回家
Megatron may be evil,
威震天虽然邪恶无比
but I believe he will use the keys for their intended purpose.
但我相信他会让这些钥匙物尽其用的
Then I say we let him keep them and do the work for us.
那干嘛不让他拿去 也省了咱们的麻烦？
W... I mean, what difference does it make who restores Cybertron?
我是说 由谁来复苏塞博特恩有区别吗？
If Megatron revives Cybertron,
如果威震天让塞博特恩重生了
he will no doubt use it to his political advantage.
他必定会借此来扩大自己的政治影响
Y-you lost me.
这…我…听不懂了
In all likelihood,
十有八九
the leader of the Decepticons will portray himself as our planet's savior
霸天虎的头目会将自己描绘为救世主
and brand all Autobots as war criminals.
将汽车人污蔑为战犯
The grand deception continues.
继续这场巨大的骗局…
Megatron's so-called "achievement" could influence Cybertron for eons to come,
威震天的“功绩”可能会影响塞博特恩几百万年
poisoning the sparks and minds of its returning citizens...
荼毒返回家园的塞博特恩人的火种和心灵
hardly the ideal way to begin a new age.
这可不是理想的新时代的开端
But there is hope.
但我们仍有希望
For while Megatron may have the keys,
威震天虽然已得到了“终极之钥”
he has yet to discover the existence of the Omega lock itself.
他依然没有发现“终极之锁”的存在
Omega lock?
“终极之锁？”
Wait... now you lost me.
等等…现在是我听不懂了
That which the four relics were designed to activate.
那正是“终极之钥”用以激活的东西
We must locate the device before Megatron does,
我们必须抢在威震天前面找到它
and secure it until we can recover the keys.
并严加保护 直到我们夺回钥匙
There are no more Iacon entries to decode.
可已经没有未破解的铁堡信息了
This lock could be anywhere on Earth!
“终极之锁”可能在地球上的任何地方
Actually...
事实上…
It is on Cybertron.
它在塞博特恩上
What?
什么？！
How do you know?
你是怎么知道的？
Alpha Trion revealed its location to me during the message conveyed by the Star Saber.
是钛师傅在星辰剑中所传递的信息里说的
And you didn't think to tell us.
你干嘛不早告诉我们？
Alpha Trion did not wish it so.
是钛师傅嘱咐的
With the Forge of Solus Prime,
有了“卓天越之锤”
we now possess the means of reaching Cybertron.
我们就有了回到塞博特恩的办法
I must work quickly,
我必须加紧工作
as our tactical advantage over Megatron will not last long.
以便尽快利用我们在战略上所取得的优势
Dreadwing.
骇翼
I have been searching for you.
我一直在找你
I am at your service, Lord Megatron.
随时为您效劳 威震天陛下
I recognize that Starscream's return to our ranks may be... difficult for you,
我明白红蜘蛛的归来令你有些…难堪
given the loss of your twin under his command.
毕竟你的兄弟是因他而死
But your cooperation is essential.
但你的配合是必要的
We Decepticons will be best-equipped to rule a restored Cybertron only if we are united.
霸天虎只有团结一致 才能复苏和领导塞博特恩
Understood.
属下明白
And if it pleases you, master,
假如您乐意的话 主人
I intend to reach out to our comrade... personally.
属下愿意以私人身份去和我们的战友沟通
Rise and shine!
该起床了
Your T-cog transplant was a success.
你的变形齿轮移植手术很成功
Yes, I am just that good.
没错 哥就是这么给力！
Ah... finally.
啊…终于！
I can't wait to take flight and soar above the clouds.
我都等不及飞起来 在云间穿梭了
Starscream.
红蜘蛛
I regret to inform you
很遗憾地通知你
that you will not live to spread your wings
你再也不会有机会展翅高飞了
ever again.
再也不会！
Knockout, help me!
击倒 救我！
Dreadwing, what has gotten into you?
骇翼 你到底怎么了？
Oh. Wait. This is about Skyquake, isn't it? I thought we had put that behind us!
哦！慢着！是天震的事儿吗？我还以为这事儿过去了！
So had I!
是过去了！
Casualties are an unfortunate consequence of war!
刀剑无眼 沙场伤亡乃兵家常事！
But I assure you, your twin met his end with great honor!
我保证令兄的牺牲是光荣的！
Which you disgraced by raising him from the dead!
但你玷污了他的荣耀！糟践了他的尸体！
Oh, you know about that.
呃…被你发现了…
There must be something I can do,
我一定能为你做些什么！
some form of reparation I can offer to alleviate your anguish!
我可以补偿你 减轻你的痛苦！
Your spark will suffice!
用你的火种就够了！
Dreadwing!
骇翼！
Stand down!
退下！
This desecrator must pay for his actions!
这个玷污我兄长的人必须付出代价！
You call this loyalty, master?!
您管这叫忠心吗 主人？！
I said stand down! That is an order.
我让你退下！这是命令！
One which I cannot follow.
恕难从命！
I'm okay? I'm okay!
啊…我没死！我没死！
Lord Megatron, you have my eternal thanks.
威震天陛下 小人将永感大恩大德！
Do not ever make me regret which one of you I spared.
别让我后悔今天的选择
Is it my imagination,
是我胡思乱想了
or has Optimus been acting differently
还是擎天柱最近有点不对头？
since that message from Alpha Trion?
自从他接收了钛师傅的信息之后
Yeah, he has been keeping things from us.
嗯…他是隐瞒了咱们一些事
Even Ratchet's out of the loop.
连救护车他都瞒着
Well, give me one good reason
给我一个理由
Optimus couldn't trust his own teammates,
为什么擎天柱不能信任我们这些队友？
why he couldn't have told us about the Omega lock.
隐瞒了“终极之锁”的存在？
Because if he had,
因为如果他说了的话
Megatron would've pulled it out of my head with his patch.
威震天就会从我的脑袋里得到这信息…用那读心设备
Like it matters.
那有什么关系
The Cons are holding all the keys anyway.
反正虎子们已经得到所有钥匙了…
Tick tock, Knockout. Tick tock!
时间不等人啊 击倒！
Megatron's expecting results,
威震天正等待结果呢！
and given what we just witnessed,
你也看到他现在心情很差
I would say that we cannot afford to disappoint our master.
我说咱们可决不能让主人失望了！
We?
“咱们”？
Unless nagging counts,
你连根手指都没动
I haven't seen you lift a finger!
就会在一边絮叨！
I am the one who brought him the keys.
我已经为他弄回来钥匙了
Do I really need to prove myself further
我用不着再靠弄清钥匙的用法…
by deciphering how they operate, too?
来证明自己的价值了吧？
Well, perhaps if my research hadn't been sidelined by someone's cosmetic surgery,
哼…要不是某人让我给他做了整形手术
I might be further along right now!
我的研究没准儿已经大有进展了!
Oh, just give it here!
哼…还是给我看看吧！
Oh, gee. Why didn't I think of that?
哦 天呐 我怎么没想到这招？
Do you think...
你也这么想的吗…？
Ready... go!
准备好了？插！
Hahaha. And that is why Dreadwing is pushing up lug nuts.
哈哈哈 这就是为什么骇翼只配拧螺钉
And we are not.
…而我们坐办公室
Of course!
原来如此！
Keys are useless without something to unlock.
如果没有“锁”的话 “钥匙”的存在就毫无意义了
Target the space bridge for Cybertron.
将太空桥指向塞博特恩！
Yet another astonishing convergence of magic and science,
又是一个惊人的魔幻般的科学奇迹
courtesy of the ancients.
感谢先祖遗赠
And our leader.
还有咱们的头儿
It's hard to believe... a few swings of that hammer, and bam!
难以置信 仅仅挥舞了几下锤子 砰的一下！
Our ground bridge is now a space bridge.
环陆桥就变成太空桥了
Our sensors are detecting a massive Energon burst occurring outside Earth's atmosphere.
探测器检测到地球大气层外有大规模能量爆发
A surge of that kind could only mean one thing...
这种爆发只有一种可能…
Activation of another space bridge.
另一座太空桥被启动了！
Megatron has discovered that the Omega lock is on Cybertron.
威震天已经发现“终极之锁”在塞博特恩了
It appears we have lost our advantage.
看起来咱们已经失去了优势
But with Megatron unaware that we now possess the means of interstellar travel,
但威震天并不知道我们也可以星际旅行了
the element of surprise remains in our favor.
只要出其不意 攻其不备 我们仍有机会
We must embark on this mission with every resource at our disposal.
为了这次的任务 我们必须祭出所有看家法宝
Starscream. Assume command in my absence.
红蜘蛛 我不在的期间由你指挥
I would be honored, master.
荣幸之至 主人！
What's he forging now?
他又在打造什么呢？
Megatron must be stopped, no matter the cost.
必须阻止威震天 不惜一切代价！ （86大电影台词）
According to the landmarks displayed by the keys,
根据钥匙显示的标志物
the object we seek is located deep the within the Sea of Rust.
我们寻找的目标就深埋于“锈海”之中
Uh, n-no, Ratchet. It's Jack.
不 救护车 是我 杰克
Is something wrong?
有什么事发生了吗？
'Cause school's been out for almost an hour, and
放学都快一个小时了
no one's showed to pick us up.
还没人来接我们
That is because the entire team is rather... indisposed at the moment.
那是因为这会儿整个小队都…有事在身
I suggest you obtain an alternate method of transport.
我建议你们今天换种方式回家吧
What's he saying?
他说什么？
Eh... The bots are busy.
嗯…轮子们忙着呢
Then tell Ratchet to come get us!
那就让救护车来接咱们嘛
It's not like he has anything else to do!
他可是个大~闲~人~
Just go home!
总之你们先回家
I will be in touch later!
我稍后再联系你们
He... hello?
喂？喂？
He hung up.
他挂掉了
What crawled up his tailpipe and died?
他又在搞什么飞机？
Did Ratchet tell you what's going on?
他有告诉你出什么事了吗？
No. They seem to be keeping us in the dark a lot lately.
没有 他们最近好像一直神秘兮兮的
Wha... what just happened?
怎么？发生什么事了？
Smokescreen?
烟幕？
But that's impossible.
这怎么可能！
The Autobots do not possess the means to...
汽车人应该没法到达…
Crush them!
干掉他们！
Defend the keys!
保护好钥匙！
I bested your little blade once,
我已经击碎过一次你的剑了
and I shall do it again!
大不了再来一次！
I will have those keys,
如果拿不回钥匙
or I will have your sparks!
我就收了你们的火种！
I can help with the last part.
后面那件事我可以代劳！
The spark extractor!
火种剥离器！
Starscream!
红蜘蛛！
The Autobots have seized the Omega keys.
汽车人已经抢走了“终极之钥”
Send reinforcements immediately!
立刻派援军过来！
Actually, lord Megatron,
这个嘛 威震天陛下
Soundwave has been briefing me on recent developments,
声波和我说了近期的一些情况
and we may have a more effective solution.
我们或许已经有了更有效的解决办法
Our head start won't last long.
咱们不会领先太久的
This is where Alpha Trion said we'd find it, right?
这就是钛师傅说的地点 对吗？
These are the coordinates.
坐标是没错
Doesn't look like much.
看起来不像啊
Ratchet, we have located the Omega lock.
救护车 我们已经找到“终极之锁”了
At last.
终于…
According to Alpha Trion,
根据钛师傅所言
the Omega lock is a conduit to the very Allspark itself.
“终极之锁”就是直接联通火种源的渠道
Optimus, an honor like this
擎天柱 如此重大的荣誉
shouldn't belong to me.
不应该属于我
Autobots,
汽车人
I would suggest that you put a halt to your task...
我建议你们停下手头的工作
and hand over those keys.
把钥匙交给我
And why would we do that?
凭什么？
So that I may hand over the humans.
就凭这些人类都在我手里
And if we refuse?
如果我们拒绝呢？
Then I will have no choice but to open the pods,
那我别无选择 只好打开那些舱体
exposing your pets to Cybertron's toxic atmosphere.
让你们的宠物暴露在塞博特恩剧毒的空气之中
And then
然后
we can all watch them instantly perish, together.
我们就可以看着他们一起…痛苦地死去！